{"1": {"question": "What is the lieder set work?", "correct": "Fruhlingstraum from Winterreise D. 911 by Schubert", "incorrect": ["Fruhlingstraum from Summerreise D.911 by Schubert", "Winterstraum from Fruhlingrreise D.911 by Schubert", "We Are Bulletproof : The Eternal by BTS (highly recommend)"]}, "2": {"question": "What does Fruhlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Dream of spring", "incorrect": ["Dream of summer", "Spring Day", "Dream of flowers"]}, "3": {"question": "What does Winterreise mean?", "correct": "Winter's journey", "incorrect": ["No More Dream", "Cold journey", "Lonely journey"]}, "4": {"question": "How many songs are in Winterreise and which number is Fruhlingstraum? (Respective)", "correct": "24, 11", "incorrect": ["14, 11", "34, 22", "24, 23"]}, "5": {"question": "What was a domestic factor in the development of the Romantic Lied?", "correct": "The growing availability and popularity of the piano and its presence in homes across a range of social classes.", "incorrect": ["The growing popularity of singing and availability of good teachers across a range of social classes.", "People's daughters transforming into ARMY fangirls, which led to composers panicking and introducing Romantic Lied.", "The decreasing popularity of Classical Lied among citizens which led composers to introduce Romantic Lied."]}, "6": {"question": "What was a factor in the development of Lied originally thought of by philosopher Johann Gottfried Herder?", "correct": "That language could unify all social classes, which sparked interest in lower classes.", "incorrect": ["That BTS would top the charts, so composers hurried to retain people's interest", "That music could unify all social classes, which sparked interest in lower classes.", "That language could only be appreciated by upper classes, which sparked an uprising in the lower classes."]}, "7": {"question": "Why did composers begin to focus on the piano accompaniment of Lieder?", "correct": "They realised the potential it had to support the text in a range of expressive ways.", "incorrect": ["They realised that it had previously had too great a role.", "They realised that BTS was too good at singing so they had to divert their attention to where they were not yet beaten.", "Their audiences were becoming dissatisfied with the piano part, so the composers had to adapt."]}, "8": {"question": "What is a song cycle?", "correct": "A unified collection of songs written to be performed in sequence.", "incorrect": ["A collection of songs written to be performed in a sequence of the performer's choice.", "A song with eleven unified parts to be performed in sequence. ", "A loop of the top ten BTS songs that plays ten times."]}, "9": {"question": "When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1838", "1848", "1997"]}, "10": {"question": "Who wrote the poem Schubert set in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "Wilhelm Muller", "incorrect": ["Suga", "Wilfred Muller", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe"]}, "11": {"question": "Schubert - What is a recurring idea in the text?", "correct": "The contrast between dreams and reality", "incorrect": ["The personalities of BTS members", "The contrast between love and loneliness", "The similarities between the narrator's past life and his dreams"]}, "12": {"question": "Which of the following is NOT a means through which composers unify song cycles?", "correct": "The songs are in the same time and key.", "incorrect": ["The songs are linked by explicit recollection of musical motifs between certain songs.", "There is often an implicit narrative thread.", "The songs are presented as musically independent numbers and the relationship is more implicit."]}, "13": {"question": "How does the changing music of Fruhlingstraum reflect its text?", "correct": "The 'happier' sections are symbolic of warmth and dreams, while the 'sadder' sections are symbolic of coldness and reality.", "incorrect": ["The slower sections are reflective of reminiscing dreams, while the faster sections reflect the poet's haste to focus on reality.", "The happier sections symbolise Schubert's love for Kpop, while the sadder sections convey Schubert's distaste for antis.", "The minor sections reflect the poet's old and harsh life, while the major sections reflect the great new life he has found."]}, "14": {"question": "What is the main subject matter of Winterreise?", "correct": "A poet who realises his destiny to always wander in solitude and perhaps never know love, companionship and rest.", "incorrect": ["A poet who must journey the world forever in search of something that does not exist.", "The hardships endured by BTS, which make international ARMYs sad because they can't help their oppas in Korea ðŸ˜¢", "A wandering shepherd who is lost and cannot find his way home to his loved ones."]}, "15": {"question": "Comment on how Schubert treats the piano accompaniment in Fruhlingstraum.", "correct": "It imitates not only concrete imagery but evokes a feeling far more powerful than the text could.", "incorrect": ["It creates implicit imagery and imitates the feeling created by the text", "It is barely heard as Schubert intended for the voice to be the prominent part.", "It is the prominent part, bringing out the main imagery and themes in the piece."]}, "16": {"question": "How has Schubert set the six stanzas of poetry used in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "ABCABC", "incorrect": ["ABBCBB", "AABCCB", "ABACAA"]}, "17": {"question": "How is the music in Fruhlingstraum used to assist the story in Section A?", "correct": "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the siciliana pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords.", "incorrect": ["Section A adopts a direct, folk-like style with the help of the melisma pattern, associated with beautiful and floral themes", "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the napolitana pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords.", "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the florentine pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords."]}, "18": {"question": "How is the music in Fruhlingstraum used to assist the story in Section B?", "correct": "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of short, sharp block chords. ", "incorrect": ["The tempo decreases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of sharp, chromatic chords.", "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of harsh and fast rolling chords.", "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of gentle block chords."]}, "19": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert write?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["Over 60", "Over 6000", "Over 2013"]}, "20": {"question": "Schubert - What are the metric qualities of the verse?", "correct": "It is written in iambic trimeter (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "incorrect": ["It is written in iambic pentameter (unstressed-stressed)", "It is written in iambic pentameter (stressed-unstressed)", "It is written in iambic trimeter (stressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "21": {"question": "How is the structure of Fruhlingstraum effective as a narrative?", "correct": "Quatrains A are about the poet's dreams. Quatrains B are about his sudden awakening to reality. Quatrains C evoke the poet's yearning to return to his dreams.", "incorrect": ["Quatrains A are about reality. Quatrains B are about his unpleasant dreams. Quatrains C evoe the poet's yearning to return to reality.", "Quatrains A are about the poet's dreams. Quatrains B are about his sudden awakening to reality. Quatrains C evoke the poet's haste to flee his dreams.", "Quatrains A are about the poet's "]}, "22": {"question": "Which of the following does Schubert NOT use to effectively contrast the three ideas in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "Changes of instrumentation and texture", "incorrect": ["Changes of style", "Changes of modality and key", "Changes of tempo and meter"]}, "23": {"question": "What is the role of the piano in Lieder?", "correct": "It is an accompaniment of equal prominence to the text that supports the ideas and feelings of the text in expressive ways.", "incorrect": ["It is the prominent part, overpowering the text and expressively creating the main feelings and ideas.", "It is an accompaniment of less importance than the text that has little musical value, occasionally chipping in.", "It is a part of equal prominence to the voice and it introduces all the themes while the voice supports the ideas and feelings."]}, "24": {"question": "Schubert - What does the siciliana pattern found in the 4-bar introduction NOT present?", "correct": "Images of mountainous landscapes", "incorrect": ["Pastoral themes", "Images of nature", "Folk-like musical 'image' to the audience"]}, "25": {"question": "Schubert - What is the intention of the iambic trimeter used in the text?", "correct": "To promote a folk-like simplicity and 'artlessness' to the text", "incorrect": ["To demote a folk-like simplicity and 'artlessness' to the text", "To promote a delicacy and 'artfulness' to the text", "To promote images of sophistication for the audience"]}, "26": {"question": "Schubert - What is the final foot in the first line of each pair?", "correct": "An amphibrach", "incorrect": ["An iamb", "A reptibrach", "A trimeter", "A nudibranch"]}, "27": {"question": "Schubert - Do the main points of stress remain constant in the text?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Yes except for one instance", "Only for one instance"]}, "28": {"question": "What is a melisma?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A kind of rhythm associated with folkish, pastoral themes", "A term used to describe singing one note per syllable", "A pair of notes sung to one syllable"]}, "29": {"question": "Schubert - How is the setting of the text?", "correct": "Typical of Lied: it is mostly syllabic and the rare melismas occupy no more than 2 notes", "incorrect": ["Typical of Lied: it is rarely syllabic and melismas are found abundantly", "Untypical of Lied: it is rarely syllabic and almost every syllable is a melisma", "Typical of Lied: it is all syllabic."]}, "30": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following is not represented by the major sections?", "correct": "Wealth", "incorrect": ["Dreaming", "Spring/warmth", "Love"]}, "31": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following is not represented by the minor sections?", "correct": "Poverty", "incorrect": ["Reality", "Winter/coldness", "Loneliness"]}, "32": {"question": "Schubert - How is the material written?", "correct": "Almost completely diatonic without modulation", "incorrect": ["Almost completely chromatic with much modulation", "Almost completely diatonic with much modulation", "Very well "]}, "33": {"question": "Schubert - How does the piano foreshadow the singer's line?", "correct": "In the four-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH", "incorrect": ["In the four-bar introduction by playing the melody in LH", "In the eight-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH", "In the ten-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH"]}, "34": {"question": "Schubert - What is/are the predominant key(s) of the song?", "correct": "F major and F minor", "incorrect": ["E flat major and E flat minor", "G major and G minor", "D major and D minor"]}, "35": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following keys are not used as [at least] brief modulations?", "correct": "D minor", "incorrect": ["C minor", "B flat major", "E flat minor"]}, "36": {"question": "Schubert - What does the 'D' in D.911 mean?", "correct": "The catalogue of Schubert's works made by Otto Deutsch", "incorrect": ["A form of cataloguing created by Ottoman Deutsch", "Dani :))", "The catalogue of Schubert's works made by Otto Dutch"]}, "37": {"question": "Schubert - What does the '911' in D.911 mean?", "correct": "It is his 911th work, ordering chronologically", "incorrect": ["Jet Fuel conspiracy theories.", "It is his 911th individual song/piece", "It is his 911th work, ordering alphabetically"]}, "38": {"question": "What does Schnell mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Very fast", "Not too fast"]}, "39": {"question": "What does Etwas bewegt mean?", "correct": "With some movement", "incorrect": ["With much movement", "With very little movement", "With no movement"]}, "40": {"question": "What does Langsam mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Fast", "Not too slow", "Very slow"]}, "41": {"question": "Schubert - What keys were the song originally written in?", "correct": "A major and A minor", "incorrect": ["F major and F minor", "G major and G minor", "E flat major and E flat minor"]}, "42": {"question": "Schubert - Why was the song transposed?", "correct": "To suit a lower voice", "incorrect": ["To suit a higher voice", "Because they felt like it", "So it was more accessible to all voices"]}, "43": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas A?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["2/4", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "44": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas B?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["2/4", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "45": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas C?", "correct": "2/4", "incorrect": ["6/8", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "46": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas A?", "correct": "F major", "incorrect": ["F minor", "E flat major", "G major"]}, "47": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas B?", "correct": "F minor", "incorrect": ["F major", "E flat minor", "E flat major"]}, "48": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas C?", "correct": "F major - F minor", "incorrect": ["E flat major - E flat minor", "G major - G minor"]}, "49": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "incorrect": ["Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "Settled, diatonic, rarely using the tonic chord"]}, "50": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "incorrect": ["Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "Flowing and carefree, often using melismas, with few leaps"]}, "51": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "incorrect": ["Arpeggiated chords", "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "Flowing block chords in continuous triplet rhythm"]}, "52": {"question": "How is Schubert's type of strophic form different from simple strophic form?", "correct": "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&4, 2&5, 3&6) rather than for every stanza", "incorrect": ["Schubert uses different music for each stanza", "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&2, 3&4, 5&6) rather than for every stanza", "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&2&3, 4&5&6) rather than for every stanza"]}, "53": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "incorrect": ["Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "Unsettled, chromatic, infrequent key changes"]}, "54": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "incorrect": ["Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, narrow leaps (mostly descending)"]}, "55": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "incorrect": ["Arpeggiated chords", "Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "Detached block chords and octaves"]}, "56": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "incorrect": ["Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "Very resolute and unquestioning"]}, "57": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "incorrect": ["Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "Sad (minor key, narrow pitch range) then simple (mostly quavers, wider pitch range)"]}, "58": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Arpeggiated chords", "incorrect": ["Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "Block chords"]}, "59": {"question": "Schubert: What is the instrumentation of the piece?", "correct": "Voice and piano", "incorrect": ["Solo instrument and piano", "Orchestra", "String quartet", "Two pianos"]}, "60": {"question": "Schubert: What does FrÃ¼hlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Spring dream", "incorrect": ["Winter dream", "Fruity Plum", "Violin", "Autumn dream"]}, "61": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of song is it?", "correct": "An art song", "incorrect": ["A pop song", "hell nah", "A sing song sang sung", "An instrumental song"]}, "62": {"question": "Schubert: What is D. 911", "correct": "Catalogue of his works", "incorrect": ["A random letter followed by a number", "Doomsday, 911 incident", "His 911th work", "A magazine catalogue"]}, "63": {"question": "Schubert: Who wrote the text for the work?", "correct": "Wilhelm MÃ¼ller", "incorrect": ["J.K. Rowling", "Marcus Hildebrandt", "Leo", "Morenz Bittermann"]}, "64": {"question": "Schubert: What does Lied mean in German?", "correct": "Song", "incorrect": ["Piece", "Music", "Piano", "Past tense for 'lie'"]}, "65": {"question": "Schubert: How many songs are in the set called Winterreise?", "correct": "24", "incorrect": ["11", "16", "4", "911"]}, "66": {"question": "Schubert: In which place is FrÃ¼hlingstraum in the set called Winterreise?", "correct": "11th", "incorrect": ["12th", "24th", "2nd", "DNF"]}, "67": {"question": "Schubert: What does Lied mean as a musical genre designation?", "correct": "A song set to German text", "incorrect": ["A song set to Italian text", "A piece of music with words", "Words with a piece of music", "A piece with words of music"]}, "68": {"question": "Schubert: How far back in time do Lied go?", "correct": "The Middle Ages", "incorrect": ["Jesus times", "The Renaissance", "The Dark Ages", "Prehistoric times (e.g. dinosaur)"]}, "69": {"question": "Schubert: In what time period did Lied develop to widespread recognition?", "correct": "The nineteenth century", "incorrect": ["Jesus times", "The eighteenth century", "10 minutes", "The seventeenth century"]}, "70": {"question": "Schubert: The devleopment of the Lied into widespread recognition had its roots where?", "correct": "The second half of the eighteenth century", "incorrect": ["The first half of the eighteenth century", "In the ground", "The second half of the seventeenth century", "The first half of the nineteenth century"]}, "71": {"question": "Schubert: What are the main reasons for the development of Lied into widespread recognition?", "correct": "The growth of German as a literary language, and how language can help social cohesion", "incorrect": ["The growth of Nazi Germany and Hitler's mo", "The growth of German as a literary language, and the development of Germany into a first-world nation", "The spread of European music across the world, and how language can help social cohesion", "Food from Germany becoming more popular around the world, and the love of their toilets"]}, "72": {"question": "Schubert: Who was at the forefront of the development of Lied into widespread recognition?", "correct": "Johann Wolfang von Goethe", "incorrect": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "Heinrich Mitter", "Elmar Preiszner", "Ralf Reiter"]}, "73": {"question": "Schubert: What idea was developed by Johann Gottfried Herder?", "correct": "Language is the most powerful determinant of social cohesion", "incorrect": ["Music is the most powerful determinant of social cohesion", "The reason for the combination of music and language is that it sounds good", "That German food is tasty", "Language is the key tool of communication within a society"]}, "74": {"question": "What happened to Joe mama?", "correct": "They changed their last name to papa", "incorrect": ["They changed their last name to Biden", "Died in a hole R.I.P.", "Stopped practising saxophone so got spanked", "Joe"]}, "75": {"question": "Schubert: Whyy were peasants interested in Lied?", "correct": "The idea that Lied united everyone into one class", "incorrect": ["Lied gave them an opportunity to become rich performing it", "Lied let them understand what it was like to be in the upper class", "Peasants had a natural musical aptitude and therefore found it easier to learn and play", "They had nothing else to do"]}, "76": {"question": "Hello", "correct": "Goodbye", "incorrect": ["Die", "Why", "Hi", "Sigh"]}, "77": {"question": "Schubert: Why was much of the German poetry written in the early stages try to disconnect from the sophistication of the town/city?", "correct": "Town dominated by Italian opera, didn't want that style of music", "incorrect": ["Town dominated by Italian opera so they tried to rip it off outside of town", "The town was dominated by French opera, didn't want that style of music", "Town was dominated by German opera, but they didn't want that genre of music", "The sophistication of the urbanised areas did not suit the lifestyle of the peasants"]}, "78": {"question": "Schubert: The striving of German poetry during late 18th to early 19th Centuries toward oral folk traditions was for what purpose?", "correct": "People wanted an art that was unmediated by artificial formal conventions", "incorrect": ["People wanted music that had no connection to the music of the wealthy", "To revive folk music as it was very popular when it was around", "To remember and respect the ancestors of their music", "People wanted an art form that was not influenced by wealth or power"]}, "79": {"question": "Schubert: The urges for an art that was unmediated by artificial conventions (e.g. Italian opera) was amplified by what?", "correct": "The emerging Romantic movement", "incorrect": ["The emerging classical movement", "The emerging jazz movement", "Donald Trump's unwillingness to back down", "The emerging renaissance movement"]}, "80": {"question": "Schubert: What did the emerging Romantic movement emphasise?", "correct": "Unfettered expressions of feeling and emotion rather than the abstract appreciation of form", "incorrect": ["Undisturbed expressions of abstract appreciation of form rather than those of feeling and emotion", "The serious lack of aid provided by developed countries to developing countries", "Expressive techniques that were unique to the Romantic movement", "The emerging Romantic composers"]}, "81": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of feeling could this kind of music inspire in the individual?", "correct": "Feelings of the power of nature and awe and wonder", "incorrect": ["Feelings of the power of nature and resentment towards it", "Feelings of the weakness of nature and its dependence on humankind", "The awe and wonder inspired by a burrito", "How bad BTS is at making music (jk they don't make music)"]}, "82": {"question": "Schubert: What effect did the growing availability and popularity of the piano have on the development of the Romantic Lied?", "correct": "Led to the increasing numbers of German Lied being produced, due to presence in peoples' homes", "incorrect": ["Led to a serious shortage of piano teachers", "Led to a boom in the musical instrument manufacturing industry", "Led to the increasing numbers of German Lied being produced due to the lack of piano teachers", "Led to increasing numbers of home insurance claims due to the increased presence of pianos in peoples' homes"]}, "83": {"question": "Schubert: What caused composers to elevate the piano's role to support the text in Lied?", "correct": "The capacity for the piano to provide a level of inflection and subtlety not achievable on harpsichord", "incorrect": ["The capacity for the harpsichord to provide a level of inflection and subtelty not achievable on a piano", "The ability of the piano to play a variety of note durations and dynamics not achievable on a harpsichord", "The way the piano is able to play in a much larger range not achievable on harpsichord", "The ability to open the lid of the piano which is a cool function"]}, "84": {"question": "Schubert: Who was the first composer to realise the potential for a fusion of German poetic setting and sophisticated accompaniment", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Bach", "Finzi", "Xi Jinping"]}, "85": {"question": "Schubert: How many Lieder did Schubert compose in his career?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["Over 800", "Under 100", "Under 600", "Over 1000"]}, "86": {"question": "Schubert: How are song cycles unified?", "correct": "All the songs are composed by the same composer, words from same poet, and have references to a particular theme or tell the same story", "incorrect": ["All the songs were composed by the same composer but the words were from different poets, and the dynamics were the same", "The songs were composed by different composers and the words are composed by different poets, and the story is different", "A binder, maybe some paper clips or staples", "By recurring motifs and ideas, also by using the same modes/keys"]}, "87": {"question": "Schubert: Who was the first composer to link individual Lieder together into unified collections?`", "correct": "Beethoven", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Finzi", "Schubert", "Xi Jinping"]}, "88": {"question": "Schubert: What was Beethoven's first song cycle?", "correct": "An die ferne Geliebte Op. 98", "incorrect": ["Seufzer eines Ungeliebten - Gegenliebe WoO 118", "Liederkreis, Op. 39", "Dichterliebe", "The Dark Side of the Moon, Op. Pink Floyd"]}, "89": {"question": "Schubert: How many different approaches to a song cycle emerged?", "correct": "Two", "incorrect": ["Three", "Four", "One", "Ten"]}, "90": {"question": "Schubert: What was Beethoven's approach to song-cycles?", "correct": "Link the songs  by explicit recollection of musical motives between certain of the individual numbers", "incorrect": ["Link the songs by using a consistent range of dynamics and expressive techniques throughout the songs", "Link the songs through the use of musical ideas that remained the same throughout every song", "Present the songs as musically independent numbers and allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "Link the songs as musically reliant variables on the dominant seventh dimished chord of the tonic mode major key"]}, "91": {"question": "Schubert: What was the non-Beethoven approach to song-cycles?", "correct": "Present the songs as musically indepenedent numbers and to allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "incorrect": ["Link the songs by explicit recollection of musical motifs between certain of the individual numbers", "Link the songs through the use of musical ideas that remained the same throughout every song", "Present the songs as musically dependent numbers and allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "Link the songs as musically reliant variables on the dominant seventh dimished chord of the tonic mode major key"]}, "92": {"question": "Schubert: Which approach to song cycles was favoured by Schubert?", "correct": "The non-Beethoven one", "incorrect": ["The Beethoven one", "Both of them, because Franz likes variety", "Neither, because he brought about a third style that was his own and more obscure", "The Mozart one"]}, "93": {"question": "Schubert: When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1928", "1826", "1905", "2020"]}, "94": {"question": "Schubert: Did Wilhelm MÃ¼ller consider the poems as a cycle?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Probably", "Why not"]}, "95": {"question": "Schubert: In which perspective is the poem told from?", "correct": "First person", "incorrect": ["Second person", "Third person", "Fourth person", "Patient zero"]}, "96": {"question": "Schubert: How is the poet introduced in the set of poems?", "correct": "Leaving a village, passing the gate of his lost love he won in spring but has now lost", "incorrect": ["Leaving a village, passing the bakery at which he always used to buy bread from", "Entering a village, passing the gate of his lost love he won in spring but has not lost", "Leaving a village, passing his home where many memories were created", "Entering a village, smelling the delicious smells of baked bread and the pretty sights"]}, "97": {"question": "Schubert: In which sense is the poet on a journey?", "correct": "Physical and psychological", "incorrect": ["Physical and spiritual", "Spiritual and psychological", "Environmental and psychological", "Biological and psychological"]}, "98": {"question": "Schubert: What is an idea in the text that MÃ¼ller constantly returns to?", "correct": "Constrast between illusion and reality", "incorrect": ["Contrast between Spring and Winter", "Contrast between walking and sitting", "Contrast between dreams and nightmares", "Contast between love and loneliness"]}, "99": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of attitude does the poet have?", "correct": "He is an outcast who will wander in solitude and never know companionship", "incorrect": ["He is highly likeable and will always have the companionship and love from others", "He is an outcast who will wander in companionship and love", "He is an extrovert who will wander in solitude and never know companionship", "He is an outcast who has many friends and his highly likebale"]}, "100": {"question": "Schubert: How is the higher awareness on the part of the poet expressed?", "correct": "He refers to the dreams of others and he knows the cold reality that awaits everyone", "incorrect": ["He refers to the dreams of higher beings and knows the cold reality that awaits everyone", "He refers to the dreams of others and he knows the pleasant reality that awaits everyone", "He refers to his own dreams and can see the future that awaits everyone", "The poet is able to see the cold reality that awaits everyone through his own dreams"]}, "101": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of rhyme scheme does FrÃ¼hlingstraum have?", "correct": "abcabc", "incorrect": ["aabaac", "ababab", "abcdab", "aabbabababaaabbabababbabababbaababbabababababbababbab"]}, "102": {"question": "Schubert: What is the poet trying to promote in the text?", "correct": "A folk-like simplicity and artlessness", "incorrect": ["A folk-like complexity and artfulness", "The simplicity of the text", "A city-like complexity and thoughtfulness", "A city-like simpleness and artlessness"]}, "103": {"question": "Schubert: In some songs in the set Winterreise, the poet dreams himself, and awakens to a harsh reality. Is this the case in FrÃ¼hlingstraum?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["Maybe", "I don't know, you tell me", "Most likely", "It is possible"]}, "104": {"question": "Schubert: How many quatrains does FrÃ¼hlingstraum contain?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["8", "4", "2", "1"]}, "105": {"question": "Schubert: Each line in the poem comprises a loose what?", "correct": "Iambic trimeter", "incorrect": ["Iambic pentameter", "Grip on reality", "Iambic dimeter", "Iambic tetrameter"]}, "106": {"question": "Schubert: How can the poetic meter throughout the poem be described?", "correct": "Simple and consistent", "incorrect": ["Complex and irregular", "Complex and unpredictable", "Simple yet unpredictable", "Complex and consistent"]}, "107": {"question": "Schubert: How are the lines grouped?", "correct": "In pairs", "incorrect": ["In threes", "In fours", "In groups of ten thouSAND MILLION BILLION TRILLION GAZILLION", "Individually"]}, "108": {"question": "Schubert: How many metric feet are there in each line?", "correct": "Three", "incorrect": ["Two", "Four", "Seventeen", "Eleven thousand, nine hundred and eighty-four point three"]}, "109": {"question": "Schubert: What do the metric feet in most cases consist of?", "correct": "iambs (unstressed-stressed)", "incorrect": ["amphibrach (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "pyrrhic (unstressed-unstressed)", "dactyl (stressed-unstressed-unstressed)", "anapest (unstressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "110": {"question": "Schubert: In the first line of each pair, the final foot is what?", "correct": "amphibrach (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "incorrect": ["iambs (unstressed-stressed)", "pyrrhic (unstressed-unstressed)", "dactyl (stressed-unstressed-unstressed)", "anapest (unstressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "111": {"question": "What renders the metre loose rather than strict?", "correct": "Short additional syllables", "incorrect": ["Long additional syllables", "Medium-lenght additional syllables", "A shortage of syllables in some places", "A surplus of unnecessary syllables"]}, "112": {"question": "Schubert: Does the two-line metric preocess apply throughout the entire verse?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Probably NOT", "Huh"]}, "113": {"question": "Schubert: What are melismas?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A group of syllables placed on one note", "A group of notes sung on a group of syllables", "A group of notes sung on two syllables", "A syllable sung on a note"]}, "114": {"question": "Schubert: What does syllabic mean?", "correct": "One syllable per note", "incorrect": ["Two sylllables per note", "Three syllables per note", "Two notes per syllable", "One syllable per three notes"]}, "115": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked A (1 and 4) symbolise?", "correct": "Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "incorrect": ["A quatrain", "Cold reality of WInter, harsh calls of birds", "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that is all illusion", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "116": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked B (2 and 5) symbolise?", "correct": "Cold reality of Winter, harsh calls of birds", "incorrect": ["Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "A quatrain", "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that is all illusion", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "117": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked C (3 and 6) symbolise?", "correct": "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that all is illusion", "incorrect": ["Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "Cold reality of Winter, harsh calls of birds", "A quatrain", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "118": {"question": "Schubert: How many times does the poem cycle through the dream-reality-longing (ABC)?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["3", "1", "4", "So many times you're gonna lose count :)"]}, "119": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section A?", "correct": "1-14", "incorrect": ["15-26", "2-15", "26-44", "1-16"]}, "120": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section B?", "correct": "15-26", "incorrect": ["13-25", "44-43", "15-28", "1-14"]}, "121": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section C?", "correct": "27-44", "incorrect": ["15-26", "1-14", "25-44", "27-45"]}, "122": {"question": "Schubert: How does Schubert delineate the contrasts between the different sections?", "correct": "Changes of key/mode, tempo, style, metre", "incorrect": ["Changes of key/mode, dynamics, style, texture", "Change of dynamics and tempo but not expressive techniques", "Expressive techniques, dynamics, key/mode, tempo", "Style, mode, metre, dynamics"]}, "123": {"question": "Schubert: What do major modes represent in this song?", "correct": "Dreaming, spring, warmth, love", "incorrect": ["Reality, winter, coldness, loneliness", "Reality, summer, heat, companionship", "Dreaming, winter, warmth, loneliness", "Spring, coldness, loneliness, love"]}, "124": {"question": "Schubert: What do minor modes represent in this song?", "correct": "Reality, winter, coldness, loneliness", "incorrect": ["Dreaming, spring, warmth, love", "Reality, summer, heat, companionship", "Dreaming, winter, warmth, loneliness", "Spring, coldness, loneliness, love"]}, "125": {"question": "Schubert: Which section comes closest to adopting a direct, folk song-like style?", "correct": "Section A", "incorrect": ["Section B", "Section C ", "Section D", "Sections A and B"]}, "126": {"question": "Schubert: The material in section A is almost entirely...", "correct": "Diatonic", "incorrect": ["Chromatic", "Minor", "Gone", "Changed"]}, "127": {"question": "Schubert: The material in section A is cast in how many simple phrases?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "6", "8", "1"]}, "128": {"question": "Schubert: What does etwas bewegt mean?", "correct": "With some movement", "incorrect": ["tgeweb sawte", "With patience", "With movement", "Slightly faster"]}, "129": {"question": "Schubert: How does the piano accompaniment foreshadow the singer's line in Section A?", "correct": "A brief four-bar introduction", "incorrect": ["A brief two-bar introduction", "A brief one-bar introduction", "A brief six-bar introduction", "A brief eighteen-bar introduction"]}, "130": {"question": "Schubert: What is siciliana?", "correct": "A slow musical style with lilting rhythms resembling a slow jig", "incorrect": ["A type of pizza", "A fast musical style with syncopated rhythms resembling a rondo", "A slow musical style with even rhythms resembling a waltz", "A fast musical style that has irregular rhythms resembling a six year old learning the piano"]}, "131": {"question": "Schubert: What kinds of themes are siciliana rhythms usually associated with?", "correct": "Nature and simple bucolic life", "incorrect": ["Buildings and complicated city life", "Nature and complex bucolic life", "Margherita, meat lovers, Hawaiian, pepperoni", "Simple country life and farms with cows"]}, "132": {"question": "Schubert: Where can a simple period be detected in Section A?", "correct": "Antecedent (bars 5-8) and consequent (bars 9-14)", "incorrect": ["Consequent (bars 5-8) and antecedent (bars 9-14)", "From bars 4-15", "Antecedent (bars 9-14) and consequent (bars 15-21)", "Antecedent (bars 6-9) and consequent (bars 10-15)"]}, "133": {"question": "Schubert: How does Section B contrast to Section A?", "correct": "Tempo increase, key change, mode becomes minor, accompaniment more staccato", "incorrect": ["Key change, mode becomes major, accompaniment more legato, tempo decrease", "Tempo increase, key change, mode becomes major, accompaniment more staccato", "Tempo decrase, key change, mode becomes minor, accompaniment more legato", "Tempo increase, key change, key becomes minor, accompaniment more staccato"]}, "134": {"question": "Schubert: What is sustained in the piano part by a tonic pedal in section B?", "correct": "A low tremolo", "incorrect": ["A high tremolo", "Basso continuo", "Slash chords", "An inappropriate accomapniment"]}, "135": {"question": "Schubert: What do the triplet figures marked x in section B act as?", "correct": "Jolts that destablise dream equilibrium", "incorrect": ["Jolts that reinforce the dream equilibrium", "Jolts that make the listener pee their pants", "Jolts that destablise the Winter reality", "Lead-ins to the next bars"]}, "136": {"question": "Schubert: What does schnell mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Walking", "Medium", "Speeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeed"]}, "137": {"question": "Schubert: What are augmented 6th chords?", "correct": "Chromatic chords which resolve to the dominant or sometimes the tonic", "incorrect": ["Chromatic chords which resolve to the tonic or sometimes the dominant", "The 6th is augmented (duh)", "Diatonic chords which resolve to the dominant or sometimes the tonic", "Diatonic chords which resolve to the tonic or sometimes the dominant"]}, "138": {"question": "Schubert: How are augmented 6th chords constructed?", "correct": "On the minor 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 6th above that", "incorrect": ["On the major 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 6th above that", "Intervals of minor 6ths piled on top of each other", "On the minor 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 2nd above that", "On the major 6th degree of hte scale and always include a note an augmented 2nd above that"]}, "139": {"question": "Schubert: The triplet figures marked x in section B involve inversions of what chord?", "correct": "The French augmented 6th chord", "incorrect": ["The German augmented 6th chord", "The Italian augmented 6th chord", "The French augmented 2nd chord", "The French suspended 6th chord"]}, "140": {"question": "Schubert: What is the Neopolitan 6th in bar 23?", "correct": "A supertonic triad constrcuted on the lowered 2nd degree", "incorrect": ["A supertonic triad constructed on the lowered 6th degree", "A supertonic triad constructed on the 5th degree", "A supertonic fourth constructed on the 5th degree of the 6th mode of the dominant 7th chord", "The 6th flavour of Neopolitan ice-cream"]}, "141": {"question": "Schubert: Does chromatic writing continue over the tonic pedal in bars 22-26?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Possibly", "Probably"]}, "142": {"question": "Schubert: What feeling is created by the rapid modulation, chromatic harmony, minor-mode colouring and angular accompaniment in Section B?", "correct": "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - waking up from a dream", "incorrect": ["A powerful sense of reassurance, sleepiness and calmness - like falling asleep", "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - playing a note during a rest in an orchestra", "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - waking up from a dreamless sleep", "A powerful sense of reassurance, sleepiness and calmness - like eating chocolate"]}, "143": {"question": "Schubert: What does langsam mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Fast", "Medium", "Turtle", "Speeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeed"]}, "144": {"question": "Schubert: What meter does Section C introduce?", "correct": "Simple duple", "incorrect": ["Simple triple", "Simple quadruple", "Compound duple", "Compound triple"]}, "145": {"question": "Schubert: What helps to set up a sense of stillness in section C after the agitation from section B?", "correct": "A new accompaniment pattern that remains quite constant", "incorrect": ["A new accompaniment pattern that varies a lot", "A reused accompaniment pattern that remains quite constant", "A new accompaniment that is constant in some parts and different in others", "An old accompaniment pattern that was drawn from a different song"]}, "146": {"question": "Schubert: The first two lines of text in Section C appear with a return to what key?", "correct": "The tonic major", "incorrect": ["The tonic minor", "The relative minor", "The dominant major", "The subdominant major"]}, "147": {"question": "Schubert: The first two lines in Section C are repeated, but what happens to the expected strong perfect cadence at bar 36?", "correct": "It is withheld", "incorrect": ["It is played as expected", "It is played and then repeated", "It is withheld and played two bars later", "It is played as unexpected, because they read the sheet music upside down"]}, "148": {"question": "Schubert: The arrival of the tonic in the bass is delayed until the final cadence in Section C, but what has changed regarding the mode?", "correct": "The mode is now minor", "incorrect": ["The mode is now major", "The mode is now diminished", "The mode is now dominant7", "The mode is now dark mode (iOS 14 feature)"]}, "149": {"question": "Schubert: How can the closure of Section C be described?", "correct": "Soaked with a feeling of loss and despair", "incorrect": ["Soaked with maple syrup like a pancake", "Soaked with a feeling of happiness and completion", "Soaked with a feeling of resentment and anger", "Epic"]}}